<resources>
    <string name="open">Open</string>
    <string name="close">Close</string>
    <string name="welcome">WELCOME TO CHANDIGARH</string>
    <string name="app_name">Chandigarh Tour guide app</string>
    <string name="category_monuments">Monuments</string>
    <string name="category_gardens">Gardens</string>
    <string name="category_markets">Market</string>
    <string name="category_restaurants">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="monument1">Open Hand Monument</string>
    <string name="monument1desc">This monument is the city\'s official emblem, signifying the message of unity, peace, and being "Open to give and receive." The monument was designed by the well-known 20th century architect Le Corbusier and is shaped like a giant hand, made from metal sheets that rotate to indicate the direction of the wind. It weighs approximately 50 tons and is 46 feet tall. It located in Sector 1 in the Capitol Complex, on the north side of the city. Open hand in Chandigarh, is one of the most significant monuments of the city. Rising eighty five feet above the ground the monument is designed like a "weather cock", not to show the incertitude of ideas, but to indicate symbolically the direction of wind (that is the state of affairs). The surface of the hand is coated with baked enamel in orange, green and while – the tri colors of Indian flag.</string>
    <string name="monument2">City Museum</string>
    <string name="monument2desc">The City Museum opened in 1997 to celebrate 50th anniversary of independence. The modern building houses plans, photos, models and original sketches of Chandigarhs planning and execution. The City Museum purpose is to collect, display and preserve all of the unique architecture and planning that went into Chandigarh\'s creation, as well as its future.It is located in Sector 10C. City Museum, The Government Museum and Art Gallery, Chandigarh owes its existence to the partition of the country in August, 1947. It is one of the premier institutions of India with a very rich collection of Gandharan sculptures, Pahari and Rajasthani miniature paintings. Before the partition in 1947, the collection of art objects, paintings, sculptures and decorative arts, were housed in the Central Museum, Lahore the then capital of Punjab. Of the various multi-dimensional Museums in India, the Government Museum and Art Gallery at Chandigarh occupies a very distinctive position for not only its unique collection of the objects, but also for other reasons as well. Situated in the heart of the city planned by Le Corbusier, and very close to the city centre in beautiful view of the Shivalik range of mountains, the Museum has a very sprawling and spread out campus at one side of which is located the Government College of Art. The Museum building is an attraction in view of the fact that Le Corbusier himself designed it. The Museum was inaugurated on the 6th May, 1968 under the initiative and active support of Late Dr. M.S. Randhawa, renowned connoisseur and patron of art, and the then Chief Commissioner of Chandigarh. Later a few other buildings were added in view of the growing need of the Museum's expansion. The campus in which the Museum is situated is surrounded with selective trees adding grandeur to the campus. The vast expanse of the courtyard of the Museum is dotted with some contemporary sculptures suitable for environmental display.
    </string>
    <string name="monument3">Capitol Complex</string>
    <string name="monument3desc">This is the most magnificent work of Le Corbusier – the architect of Chandigarh. Capitol Complex is the seat of the governments of Punjab and Haryana. Set against the Shivalik Hills the complex comprises of three edifices – the Secretariat, the High Court and the Legislative Assembly, representing the monumental character authority of the complex. Separated by large piazzas, the subtle and most evocative grouping of these buildings is of breath-taking beauty.</string>
    <string name="monument4">Martyr\'s Memorial</string>
    <string name="monument4desc">Just right of the Assembly building one can see the Martyr’s Memorial – a monument to pay tribute to the martyrs of the Punjab partition. The memorial consists of a square enclosure with one side elongated into a ramp by which one mounts the enclosing wall, Within the enclosure are to be symbolic figures of a prone man, a snake, and a lion set amid ruins. The concrete ramp permits one to see, from above the Capitol in its entirety and creates a promenade rising and descending. Other stunning monuments include the Tower of Shadows and  Geometric Hill.</string>
    <string name="playground1">Rajendra Park</string>
    <string name="playground1desc"> LOCATED ALONG the backdrop of Shivalik hills at far end of Chandigarh, Rajendra Park is among the oldest parks of the City Beautiful.Park was named after first President of India Rajendra Prasad who had come to the city for its inauguration in 1954. Its landscape along with that of the Capitol Complex was designed by French architect Le Corbusier.
        The park was earmarked in the original master plan and its landscape was designed by Le Corbusier. It has not been developed accordingly</string>
    <string name="playground2">Rock Garden</string>
    <string name="playground2desc">The name refers to a sculpture garden located near Sukhna Lake. The Rock garden is also known by the name Nek Chand’s Rock Garden after its founder. Nek Chand was a former government official who started cultivating this garden secretly in his spare time. He kept it hidden from the government authorities for 18 years, till 1975. The garden features several interlinked causeways that run along the waterfalls of the Sukhna Lake and is landscaped with pottery and sculptures of dancers, animals and musicians.</string>
    <string name="playground3">Rose Garden</string>
    <string name="playground3desc">Spread over 30 acres the Zakir Hussain Rose Garden is the largest botanical garden in Asia that is dedicated to roses. The garden is named after Zakir Hussain the former President of India. Apart from roses the garden also features several verities of medicinal herbs.</string>
    <string name="playground4">Pinjore Gardens</string>
    <string name="playground4desc">Also known as the Yadavindra Gardens, the Pinjore gardens were created by a Nawab under the Mughal emperor Aurangzeb. The garden was expanded and reconstructed by the Maharaja Yadavindra of the State of Patiala. The garden houses several palatial structures that display a distinct blend of the Rajasthani and Mughal styles of architecture.</string>
    <string name="playground5">ChattBir Zoo</string>
    <string name="playground5desc">Also known as the Mahendra Chaudhry Zoological Park, the zoo houses a huge number of exotic and wild animals, birds and reptiles. The thing to watch out for at this zoo is the famous lion safari.</string>
    <string name="playground6">Botanical Gardens</string>
    <string name="playground6desc">A picturesque botanical garden, located between the Rock Garden and Sukhna Lake in Sector 1 stretches to about 88 acres. The main attraction of this garden is its rock formations, small lily-pools and rare species of plants kept in the green house.
There is another botanical garden in the Punjab University. Cacti, succulent, ever green and exotic plants are arranged in each corner. This is the only place in Chandigarh where beautiful lotus flowers can be seen.
One more botanical garden is being created in Chandigarh covering an area of 117 acres which include medicinal, exotic and indigenous plants species. </string>
    <string name="market1">Sector 17 Market</string>
    <string name="market1desc">Shopping lists will be less and your bags will be small when you are standing in the Sector 17 market of Chandigarh. This place is popularly known as the City Centre and no doubt is the most crowded area of the city. Electronic goods, food, books, street shops for clothes, shoes and accessories all are available for sale here at sector 17. The affordable range of street shops and the branded stores in the next line is a great combination you can find at the Sector 17 market.</string>
    <string name="market2">Sector 11 Market</string>
    <string name="market2desc">This is also known as the main market. The areas in Chandigarh are divided in sector format because of which the market is named as sector 11. Here you can buy some fantastic Indian suits, eat chat and have a sip of coffee at CCD. This is one of the places which miss nothing except the ATM centre. Hence, the place is recommended for those who have just taken admission and willing to put some stupendous casuals and suits. This is one of the most famous markets in Chandigarh.</string>
    <string name="market3">Sector 22 Market</string>
    <string name="market3desc">The well-known sector 22-D Street in Chandigarh is a suitable place for every pocket. You can bargain as much as you can and get reasonably priced products with good quality. The widest collection of clothes, sarees, salwar kameez, party dresses, kids wear and men’s casual wear is accessible here at sector 22.  Moreover, women jewellery stores are the centre of attraction which deal in diamond, gold and artificial jewellery. This is one of the cheap markets in Chandigarh.</string>
    <string name="market4">Sector 15 Market</string>
    <string name="market4desc">Almost every college going student needs a good wardrobe in Chandigarh. More than the middle age group people a cluster of students are always observed surrounding the sector 15 market. Punjabi chat, Chinese, salons, electronic goods, clothes, bags, seasonal garments etc. are available here suiting different types of tastes buds. This is one of the main markets in Chandigarh.</string>
    <string name="restaurant1">Pirates and Platters</string>
    <string name="restaurant1desc">Pirates of Grill in the Chandigarh Industrial Area is a buffet lovers delight.  It serves up Asian, Continental and North Indian food from 11 am to 4 pm and then again from 6:30 pm to 11 pm. The buffets start at Rs 311/- and goes up to Rs 1410/- depending in the days of the week and service timings. While the place does not offer home delivery, the rest of the facilities provided are more than enough. It does have a bar that boasts of some great mixes. The USP here is that some drink or the other comes included with the buffets. Specialties include its Arabic chicken, fish in black bean sauce and alu salsa. It\'s cheesecake is unputdownable and ‘A La Carte’’ menu is also available and costs around Rs 1200/- only. This is not a very big amount considering the quality of the food served and the experience you get here.</string>
    <string name="restaurant2">Freshly Grilled Food</string>
    <string name="restaurant2desc">AJA Fresh, Grilled, Healthy at Sector 11 is a must visit for all food enthusiasts. Open from 11 am to 11 pm, this place is done up beautifully and offers free WiFi for customers who prefer to browse the internet while they gorge on food. Items on the menu include crudités and satays, vegan boxes, skinny pizzas, protein shakes, and smoothies. You will want to know that the food here has some glutton free options and the items are not that expensive. It will cost your Rs 600/- for a meal for two and we thought this place deserves a spot on this list of best restaurants in Chandigarh. You may well be on your way to this place after reading this article.</string>
    <string name="restaurant3">Ducks and Quacks</string>
    <string name="restaurant3desc">Enjoy your food outdoors at a place called the Whistling Duck on SCO 10, near Back Lane at Sector 26.  European, Asian, and Indian fare is served here along with crowd pulling facilities like free WiFi. It would be unfair for this place to dish out such tasty food and not have a bar of its own, so the Whistling Duck comes with a fully loaded bar that will surely quench your thirst. It opens at noon and serves faithful customers till 1 am. The drinks menu has a long list of beers, whiskey, rum-based, cocktails and mocktails. A must try is the soya keema Hyderabad rice and mushroom canopies.  Just carry Rs 1500/- with you and have a great eat out experience. Be adventurous and try new items that are on the menu here. You will expand your culinary horizon with the food here.t</string>
    <string name="restaurant4">Going the American Route</string>
    <string name="restaurant4desc">Brooklyn Central at the Chandigarh Industrial Area is a place with a menu that is rich in American delights. It serves food from 11 am up until midnight and is a delight for the youth and working class. This is a perfect place to brunch or spends time during a free period from college. The chicken barbecue burger is awesome and the sangria to die for. With Wifi, college goers make up the crowd here. Waffles, casseroles and tapas make up its menu, but that’s just like the tip of the iceberg with a long list behind. It would be best for you to call and make an appointment prior to your visit. An outdoor seating facility makes this place a contender on the list of best restaurants in Chandigarh.
    </string>
    <string name="restaurant5">Live Bands and Great Food at Aasma</string>
    <string name="restaurant5desc">Aasma at the Amravati NH22 Mall is a famous eatery that records a great footfall round the year. The place serves the usual Chinese, Mughlai, Continental and North Indian dishes with a  bar to hElp one guzzle down all the food. This is one restaurant that has a band performing live while you eat. It starts service at noon and closes as 3:30 pm only to open up again at 7 pm and the final order is taken by 10:30 pm.  Drinks are served from 5 pm to 7 pm. Your cravings for salads will be satisfied with their Caeser salad, sunshine pasta salad, and grilled fish morsel. The murgh khumb shorba is a crowd winner while the fresh fruit raita is a refreshing deviation from the usual. Prices are competitive and you will need to shell out at least Rs 1500/- to dine here. Nevertheless, this place is great to visit and explore the food.</string>
</resources>